Thomas Benjamin Yuill

Front End & Web Development Specialist http://www.thom-foolery.com/

Current Employment:

TheRedPin.com

http://theredpin.com Lead User Interface Developer (August 2012 – Present)

Completely rebuilt and consolidated the property maps across the site to use a front-end MVC architecture and to utilize the Google Maps v3 API. I work very closely with the back-end and feature developers to coordinate the successful creation of a RESTful JSON web service API. Additionally I worked closely with the designer to prototype, style and implement a responsive, global site layout along with various reusable UI components.

Since my hiring I have been able to raise page load times across the site by upwards of 25%. I have created a modular and maintainable JS framework to facilitate the constant growth of the product. I have devised a style framework to ensure a consistent look and feel across the rebuilt site while maintaining the older out of date pages. The agile methodology we apply to projects here at theRedPin has kept my work flow steady and manageable.

Previous Employment:

Critical Mass

http://www.criticalmass.com/ Senior Developer (November 2010 – August 2012)

Responsible for directing my team members in the front-end development and maintenance of high profile commercial web sites. The high volume of traffic required the thoughtful use of proven design and development practices to ensure the smooth and timely delivery of project milestones. I ensured my team members adhered to currently accepted web standards as closely as possible to satisfy the widest range of user agents and devices. Also worked closely with design teams to help them realize their visions and expectations within time and on budget restraints.

Clients Included: Citi bank, Adidas, Infiniti (Global account), and more

CBC

http://www.cbc.ca

User Interface Developer (September 2009 – November 2010)

I was responsible for the front-end development and maintenance of a large multimedia publication system. Working with my team members we instituted web standards and guidelines for satellite web teams to adhere to across the country. Responsibilities included writing semantic HTML, progressive CSS, re-usable user interface components, implement accessibility requirements, utilizing object oriented JavaScript and the YUI 3 framework, cross browser compatibility testing and functional backend knowledge of SSI, PHP and Java. A keen understanding of Unix Web Server environments and bash scripting was an asset.

henderson bas

http://www.theniceagency.com

Senior Interface Developer (June 2008 – September 2009)

Responsible for the front-end development and maintenance of many, large, high traffic, commercial websites. Daily activities include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Cross browser compatibility testing. The position required PHP, .NET, ASP and JSP knowledge. I was also the lead front-end developer for all iCoke.ca projects.

Clients Included: Coca-Cola, Nintendo, Molson, Tim Hortons, Joe Fresh, and more

henderson bas

http://www.theniceagency.com

Quality Assurance Analyst (September 2007 - June 2008)

Provided full cross-browser project testing of all digital deployments. Required writing test cases and requirements documents as well as working closely with the project managers and the development team.

Previous Projects:

Infiniti Global Redesign

http://www.infiniti.com

Rebuilt the front-end desktop and mobile interfaces of Infiniti.com's global facing site. Cross browser compatibility from IE7+, with full screen responsive background media (images and HTML 5 video). Including AJAX page transitions. Interface components were built with a modular architecture to provide drag and drop CMS usability. Included image galleries and video players, time lines, and social sharing widgets and feeds. The site makes heavy use of progressive enhancement using HTML5, CSS3 while adhering to best practices.

Adidas miteam

http://www.miteam.adidas.com/

Collaborated with a large team across 3 major cities to complete an extremely complex, dynamic product configurator. Included writing modular JavaScript components and accompanying unit test cases written with the Jasmine JS test framework. I was specifically tasked with creating a rule parsing system capable of enabling and disabling product parts and attributes depending on a series of patterned rules sets that would be defined within JSON objects.

CBC Consolidated Media Player

http://www.cbc.ca/video

Cooperated with flash developers to add new functionality and improve overall efficiency of the media portal of cbc.ca. I was brought onboard after the initial release in 2010. I instituted the pop-up player, radio player and program guide overlay menus. I refactored much of the core JavaScript framework in order to architect a true MVC pattern to facilitate maintenance and reusability.

CBC Home Page Redesign - Technical Specifications

http://www.cbc.ca

I wrote the technical specification and implementation guide for the CBC homepage redesign project. Documentation focused on the use of HTML, CSS 3 and object oriented JavaScript to reach the largest range of user devices while improving the overall design and usability of the **cbc.ca**'s main home page.

Other Projects

CBC Radio Player

www.cbc.ca/video/radio/popup

CBC: the National

http://www.cbc.ca/thenational

Coca-cola

www.icoke.ca

Molson Canadian Redesign www.molsoncanadian.ca

Nintendo

http://www.nintendo.ca

Education:

York University

4 year Bachelor of Arts in Information Technology (Social Stream)

Skills:

Technical

- HTML5 API
- Semantic HTML
- Responsive Layouts
- Rapid Prototyping
- PHP, JAVA, .NET
- Accessibility
- YUI & jQuery
- XML & JSON
- CSS 2 & 3
- JavaScript
- SVN & GIT
- UNIX

Aesthetic

- User Interface Design
- Mobile Design
- Form Design
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Sketching
- Doodling

Architecture

- User Experience and Interaction Design
- Object Oriented Design Patterns
- Technical Documentation
- Information architecture
- User Interface Design
- Wire framing
- User Testing

References and additional project information can be supplied upon request.

25 Elsie Lane Unit 138 Toronto Ontario, M6P 3N3 Canada Email: thomas.yuill@gmail.com

Linked In: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/b/902/bb6

Phone: 647.406.7056